jci.com 2014-12-09

# Privacy | Johnson Controls Inc.

This Privacy Notice (the Notice) contains the policies of Johnson Controls, Inc. (Johnson Controls) regarding the collection and use of information relating to this website (the Web Site) and all applications accessible through this Web Site (the Applications), except where noted. References to the User mean any person or company that visits or uses the Web Site or the Applications (User).           

By using the Web Site or any Application you represent that (a) you are of sufficient legal age and have authority to use the Web Site and Applications and to bind your company as applicable; and (b) you have read this Notice and consent to the use of personal information collected by Johnson Controls as described in this Notice. Johnson Controls may make changes to this Notice by posting the revised Notice on this Web Site. Please check periodically to ensure that you have reviewed the most current Notice. Using the Web Site or any Application after any change to the Privacy Notice will be deemed consent to the change.           

**U.S. - EU Safe Harbor & U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Privacy Statement **

Johnson Controls complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland.  Johnson Controls has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. 

To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, please visit

<http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

To view Johnson Controls’ certification, please visit <http://safeharbor.export.gov/companyinfo.aspx?id=21691>  

Johnson Controls also protects information received from individuals in Israel in accordance with the Safe Harbor Principles.       

**General Information Collection        **  
Johnson Controls may collect, maintain, and process information provided by or concerning Users, on and through the Web Site and the Applications. Users agree that all information they provide to Johnson Controls is accurate, current, non-misleading and relevant for the purpose provided. Users of the Applications also agree that they have the authority to provide the information submitted through the Applications, and agree that Johnson Controls may occasionally verify that authority.     

**Public Areas of the Web Site            **  
Users may visit the public areas of the Web site without disclosing any personal information about themselves, other than Johnson Controls automatic logging of basic usage data as described in Usage Data below.  

**Contact Information and “Opt-Out”           **  
If a User requests information from Johnson Controls, an e-mail or other contact information may be required in order to allow Johnson Controls to reply or for other related purposes. Johnson Controls will request only that information reasonably necessary to provide requested information or services. Users may elect to opt-out from receiving communications by (i) checking appropriate opt-in or opt-out boxes if provided on the collection form, (ii) following the instructions Opt-Out Choices below, or (iii) following the instructions described in the communication sent from Johnson Controls.  

**Registration Information       **  
To use the Web Site or Applications, Users may be required to register by providing contact information such as user ID, password, name, title, business address, business telephone number, business e-mail address and other contact information (Registration Information). Certain portions of the Registration Information may be used for determining qualifications for use of particular Applications. Johnson Controls may use Registration Information to communicate with Users regarding available transactions, changes in functionality of the Web Site or Applications, billing, help desk and other activities relating to the operation of the Web Site. Johnson Controls may also use Registration Information to send Users information about products or services available on or through the Web Site and offers made available by Johnson Controls’ business partners, which information may be sent by Johnson Controls or the business partner making the offer. Instructions on how to request that Johnson Controls not send future communications (except for those necessary for the operation of the Web Site or the Application) or that Johnson Controls not share Registration Information with third parties are contained in Opt-Out Choices below.            

**Transaction Data       **  
Johnson Controls may collect and compile information concerning interaction with the Web Site and Applications, including transactions and other use by Users (Transaction Data). Johnson Controls will use Transaction Data for its intended purpose in Johnson Controls business with, for or on behalf of the User or the User’s company. Johnson Controls will not share Transaction Data with any third party, except to the extent reasonably required in Johnson Controls business with, for or on behalf of the User or the User’s company. Johnson Controls may aggregate and/or use for its own internal purposes any Transaction Data, and may use or disclose to third parties aggregated Transaction Data not reasonably identifiable to any User or company.          

**Usage Data      **  
Johnson Controls will collect information about how Users use the Web Site and the Applications. This data may include a User's domain name, language, type of browser and operating system, Internet service provider, Internet protocol (IP) address, the site or reference directing the User to the Web Site, and the amount of time spent on the Web Site or using any Application (collectively, Usage Data). Johnson Controls may monitor and use Usage Data in aggregated form to measure the Web Site's performance and Application activity and improve the Web Site's design and functionality. Johnson Controls may also use Usage Data for security purposes or to verify transactions or other communications made in the Applications.   

**Consent to Processing            **  
By using or providing information to the Web Site and the Applications, Users understand and consent to the collection, processing and use of such information in the United States and other countries and territories, for the purposes set forth in this Notice.       

**Acceptable Disclosures          **  
Johnson Controls may use third parties to provide or perform services and functions on the Web Site and the Applications. For example, Johnson Controls may use a third-party supplier to provide functionality provided in an Application through a browser re-direction to or framed use of systems operated by that third-party supplier. Johnson Controls will make information concerning Users and their use of the Web Site and the Applications available to these suppliers, as necessary, to perform these functions. Any access to that information will be limited to the purpose for which the information was provided. The suppliers may be located throughout the world; therefore information relating to Users may be sent worldwide to countries having different privacy protection standards than the User’s country of residence. Johnson Controls may also make information concerning Users, the Web Site and the Applications, and the uses thereof, available to law enforcement personnel and agencies as required by law. Where permitted by law, Johnson Controls may also disclose such information to law enforcement personnel and agencies, or use such information as part of legal process, in order to protect its property or in support of an investigation regarding a breach of the terms of use or any unauthorized access to or use of the Web Site or the Applications.  

**Cookies**  
Johnson Controls may use information stored on a User’s computer or other access device, also called “cookies,” to make sign-in to and transactions and other activities on the Web Site more efficient. These cookies will not contain any personal information.      

**Linked Sites and Applications          **  
Johnson Controls may provide links to third parties' Web sites or applications (Linked Sites) from the Web Site or any Application. Linked Sites are not necessarily reviewed, controlled or examined by Johnson Controls. Each Linked Site may have its own terms of use and privacy policy, and Users must be familiar and comply with all such terms and policies when using Linked Sites. Johnson Controls is not responsible for the policies and practices of any Linked Site, or any additional links contained in them. These links do not imply Johnson Controls’ endorsement of the Linked Sites or any company or service. 

**Access and Changes to Personal Information         **  
A User may request to review, change, or update Registration Information or other information provided on or through the Web Site or the Applications by sending an e-mail to the Johnson Controls Privacy Office.   

**Opt-Out Choices         **  
To "opt-out" of (1) receiving communications from Johnson Controls in connection with the Web Site (except for communications necessary for the operation of the Web Site or the Applications), (2) having contact information disclosed to third parties (except as necessary for Johnson Controls to operate the Web Site and Applications, or as otherwise permitted under this Notice), or (3) any other consent previously granted for a specific purpose concerning personal or contact information, an e-mail should be sent to the Johnson Controls Privacy Office.

**Transfer of Information        **  
In the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, dissolution, or sale or transfer of the substantial assets of Johnson Controls or any of its business operations, information provided by or collected about Users may be sold, assigned, or transferred to a party acquiring all or substantially all of the equity and/or assets of Johnson Controls or its business operation so that such party may continue the operation of the Web Site and the Applications. Johnson Controls may also transfer such information to its subsidiaries and affiliates directly involved in the operation of the Web Site or any Application.         

**Security**  
Johnson Controls has implemented technology and security policies and procedures intended to reduce the risk of accidental loss or destruction of, or the unauthorized disclosure or access to, such information, reasonably appropriate to the level of the data concerned.         

**Social Security Number Protection Notice Statement         **  
JCI collects Social Security numbers in the ordinary course of its business, such as from our employees and applicants. We have implemented reasonable technical, physical and administrative safeguards to help protect the Social Security numbers. All JCI workers are required to follow these established procedures. In particular: 

  * Access to Social Security numbers is limited to those workers and service providers who have a need to access the information to perform tasks for us and our clients. 
  * Social Security numbers are only disclosed to third parties in accordance with our established policies. JCI only discloses Social Security numbers to (i) those service providers, auditors, advisors, and/or successors in interest who are legally or contractually obligated to protect them or (ii) as required or permitted by law.

**Contact; Questions; Comments; Complaints           **  
If you would like to communicate with Johnson Controls regarding privacy issues or have questions, comments or complaints about this Notice, the Web Site or any Application, please forward such communication to the Johnson Controls Privacy Office (email address: [privacy@jci.com](mailto:privacy@jci.com)).

For EU citizens, if efforts to resolve a concern within Johnson Controls are unsatisfactory, you may contact the panel of EU data protection authorities established as an independent recourse mechanism under the Safe Harbor Agreement.  Johnson Controls will cooperate with the panel of EU data protection authorities in the resolution of such enquiries.  Similarly, for Swiss citizens, you may contact the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner.
